Ceske Orphanage
دار أيتام تشيسكي
Goodness gracious, you're so...
...يا لك من ولد مشاغب
How many times must you pretend to run away before you're satisfied?
كم مرة ستغادر قبل أن يؤذن لك؟
If you do it again, you won't get dinner.
إن فعلتها مجددًا فستُحرم من العشاء
You hear me, Milos?
فهمت، (ميلوش)؟
Yes, ma'am.
نعم
Take your hands out of your pockets when talking to someone!
وأخرج يدك من جيبيك حين تكلم أحدًا
Yes, ma'am.
حاضر
For real?!
حقًا؟
Yeah. It was that blonde girl.
أجل، إنها نفس الفتاة الشقراء
You saw her on Dominican Street, right?
قلتَ بأنك شاهدتَها في شارع (دومينيكان)؟
I wonder if she lives around here?
هل تقيم بالقرب من هناك؟
Why didn't you keep following her?
لماذا لم تستمر في تتبعها؟
But I was hungry.
لأني كنتُ يومها جائعًا
In that case, let's find out where she lives...
هيا إذًا لنكتشف مكان إقامتها ونبلغ رجال الشرطة
And tell them that Mr. Grimmer didn't kill the director
ونقول لهم بأن السيد (غريمر) لم يقتل المدير
We'll prove his innocence.
سوف نثبت براءته
Prove his innocence?
نثبت براءته؟
Then Mr Grimmer will be off the hook.
وسيصير السيد (غريمر) خارج الاشتباه
That's right.
صحيح
We'll hold a meeting to come up with a plan.
سنجتمع لإعداد خطة
Milos, hurry up and finish your dinner already.
ميلوش)، هيا أكمل عشاءك بسرعة)
The Cruelest Thing
الفصل 49
This is the unlicensed orphanage where it first started.
هنا كان مقر دار الأيتام غير المرخصة
The former director of 511 kinderheim was murdered by someone here.
وهنا قُتل المدير السابق لـ (كيندرهايم 511)
The kids said that a blonde girl walked them right after it happened.
قال الأطفال بأن الفتاة الشقراء خرجت من الشقة قبيل مقتله
He restarted his experiment here.
هنا أعاد الشروع في تجاربه
Unlike the one at 511 kinderheim...
وخلافًا لتجاربه في (كيندرهايم 511)
this one was to determine the effects of love on the children.
فقد أراد هذه المرة أن يكتشف أثر الحب على الأطفال
What would you like to do?
ما رأيك؟
Should we go in?
هل ندخل؟
The police should have already removed any evidence.
لا بد أن الشرطة قد أزالوا كل الأدلة
Mr. Grimmer, what's that?
سيد (غريمر)، ما هذا؟
It's those kids.
إنهم أولئك الأطفال
The kids from this orphanage must have come back and put these notes here.
أطفال الميتم عادوا إلى هنا وعلَّقوا هذه الأوراق
"To Mr. Grimmer."
"إلى السيد (غريمر)"
Milan Boucek.
(ميلان بوتشيك)
It's a famous soccer player's card.
إنها بطاقة للاعب مشهور
This must be something precious to the children.
لا بد أنها شيء ثمين للأطفال
How should I react?
كيف يجب علي أن أتصرف؟
In this type of situation, what should I feel?
في هذا الوضع، كيف يجب علي أن أشعر؟
My emotions were stolen by 511 kinderheim.
مشاعري سُرقت في (كيندرهايم 511)
After that, I went to a special school to learn how to express emotions...
بعدها، ذهبتُ إلى مدرسة خاصة لأتعلم كيف أعبر عن مشاعري
But these types of situations are the most difficult to handle...
لكن وضعًا كهذا من الصعب استيعابه
What kind of expression would be appropriate here?
أي تعبير هو المناسب هنا؟
How about paying those kids a visit?
ما رأيك في زيارة لأولئك الأطفال؟
St. Bardejov Orphanage
ميتم القديس باردييوف
You're Mr. Grimmer?
أنت السيد (غريمر)؟
I always hear a lot about you from the children.
دائمًا أسمع عنك الكثير من الأطفال
They went out to play and haven't returned yet.
لقد خرجوا لأجل اللعب ولم يعودوا بعد
I hope they come back soon...
أتمنى أن يعودوا بسرعة
Here, take a look at this.
تفضل، انظر إلى هذا
It's the children's diary...
إنها مذكرات الأطفال
Actually, it looks more like letters addressed to you.
يبدو أن أكثرها رسائل موجهة إليك
"Mr. Grimmer, let s play soccer again."
"سيد (غريمر)، لنلعب الكرة مجددًا "
"Mr. Grimmer is bad at soccer, so I'll teach him how to get better."
"السيد (غريمر) لاعب سيئ، لذا يجب أن أدربه كي يصير أفضل"
"Mr. Grimmer, come play with us again."
"سيد (غريمر)، تعال العب معنا مجددًا "
I'm smiling now, right?
أنا أبتسم الآن صحيح؟
I learned how to do this.
لقد تعلمتُ كيف أفعل ذلك
I learned how to make a smile.
تعلمتُ كيف أرسم ابتسامة
I'm actually part of those kids' memories.
أنا الآن جزء من ذكريات أولئك الأطفال
Why would they think of me?
لماذا كان عليهم أن يفكروا بي؟
Because they all like you.
لأنهم جميعًا يحبونك
They like me...
...يحبونني
I thought about...
لقد فكرتُ من قبل، في المشاعر التي يجب أن أحس بها حين مات ولدي
Should I cry in this situation?
هل كان علي يومها أن أبكي؟
Just how much should I cry?
كم كان علي أن أبكي؟
Should I scream at the top of my lungs?
هل كان علي أن أصرخ بأعلى صوتي؟
Or should I clench my teeth?
أم كان علي أن أغلق فمي؟
Even now, I still don't know how I should have reacted.
حتى الآن لا أعرف كيف كان علي أن أتصرف
I just don't know...
...ما زلتُ لا أدري
Mr. Grimmer!
!سيد (غريمر)
Hey, Antonin...
أهلًا (أنطونين)
Mr. Grimmer, this is bad!
!سيد (غريمر)، هذا سيئ
What's wrong, Antonin?
ما المشكلة (أنطونين)؟
We just got a message from the Ceske Orphanage...
تلقينا للتو رسالة من ميتم (تشيسكي)
Something bad happened...!
!شيء فظيع حدث
Calm down, Antonin.
اهدأ يا (أنطونين)
Calm down and tell me.
اهدأ وأخبرني
We found the blonde girl!
!لقد وجدنا الفتاة الشقراء
Yesterday, we went looking for her to find out where she lives.
بالأمس، ذهبنا للبحث عن مكان إقامتها
And then Milos...
وبعدها (ميلوش)
Milos disappeared
ميلوش) اختفى)
krumlov National Hospital
مستشفى كروملوف الوطني
I see.
هكذا إذًا
The people who came to visit you were...
الناس الذين جاؤوا لزيارتك في الآونة الأخيرة
a middle-aged gentleman...
رجل في منتصف العمر
a tall German...
وألماني طويل
and a Japanese man with long hair...
ورجل ياباني طويل الشعر
Yes.
أجل
By the way, wasn't there one more person you've left out?
بالمناسبة، أليس هناك شخص آخر نسيتِه؟
According to the nurse, there was a woman with long blonde hair who also came to visit you.
وفقًا للممرضة، فقد جاءت لزيارتك أيضًا فتاة شقراء الشعر
A woman?
فتاة؟
No, a woman didn't come to visit me.
لا، لم تأت لزيارتي أي امرأة
No, the nurse was sure of it.
لا، الممرضة واثقة من ذلك
A very beautiful woman.
فتاة جميلة جدًا
Yes, she was very beautiful.
أجل، كانت جميلة جدًا
But she was actually a man.
لكن، كانت في الواقع رجلًا
I see.
فهمت
What's your name?
أنت، ما اسمك؟
Milos.
(ميلوش)
Have we met somewhere before?
هل التقينا في مكان ما من قبل؟
N-No.
كلا
What were you doing there?
ماذا كنت تفعل هنا؟
Nothing, really...
...لا شيء
You come around here a lot, don't you?
أنت تأتي إلى هنا كثيرًا صحيح؟
Y-Yeah...
أجل
Are you looking for someone?
هل تبحث عن شخص؟
Umm... my mom.
نعم... أمي
Why not come over here and have a seat?
لماذا لا تأتي إلى هنا وتجلس؟
I have some juice for you, too.
لدي عصير لك
Umm... Are you moving?
هل سترحلين؟
Why do you ask?
لماذا تسأل؟
You have a big bag...
لديك حقيبة ضخمة
and there's nothing in this room.
ولا يوجد شيء في هذه الغرفة
Does your mother live around here?
أمك... هل تعيش هنا أيضًا؟
Didn't you say you were looking for your mother?
ألم تقل بأنك كنت تبحث عن أمك؟
Yeah.
بلى
But I don't know if she actually lives around here.
لكني لا أعرف ما إذا كانت تعيش هنا
Then how are you going to find her?
إذًا كيف ستجدها؟
Do you have a picture of her?
ألديك صورة لها؟
No, I don't.
كلا
Then you don't know what she looks like.
إذًا، فأنت لا تعرف كيف تبدو
I'll know.
سأعرف
When I see her, I'll recognize her.
سأعرفها ما إن أراها
Nobody at the orphanage believes me.
لا أحد في الميتم يصدقني
They all say there's no way I'd know...
يقولون بأن من المستحيل أن أعرف
but I'll recognize my mom when I see her.
لكني سأعرف أمي ما إن أراها
And...
...وأيضًا
And?
وأيضًا؟
My mom will recognize me when she sees me, too!
فإن أمي أيضًا ستعرفني ما إن تراني
What if she pretends that she doesn't recognize you when she sees you?
ماذا لو تظاهرتْ بأنها لا تعرفك حين تراك؟
Were you born because you were wanted?
هل أنجبتك لأنها أرادتك؟
Why were you abandoned?
لماذا تركتك؟
Didn't your mother abandon you because she didn't like you?
ألم تتخلَّ أمك عنك لأنها لا تحبك؟
T-That's not true!
!كلا
Being born really isn't that uncommon...
أن يولد الأطفال ليس حدثًا نادرًا
Almost everything in this world is meant to die.
كل شيء في هذا العالم مصيره الموت
In this world, a life born is nothing more than an insignificant speck...
في هذا العالم، نشوء الحياة ليس أكثر من حدث لا معنى له
and shouldn't even be counted as an existence.
مجرد بقع تافهة في زوايا الأرض
Death is natural.
الموت طبيعي
Then why are you alive?
لماذا أنت حي؟
Is it because someone wanted you?
هل لأن أحدًا أرادك؟
Who wanted you?
من أرادك؟
What is your reason for living?
ما هو هدف حياتك؟
A girl with long blonde hair...
فتاة ذات شعر أشقر طويل
Ah, that would be Anna.
نعم لا بد أنها (آنا)
Anna?!
آنا)؟)
Does this Anna live around here?
هل تعيش هذه الـ (آنا) بالقرب من هنا؟
Yeah, I'm pretty sure her apartment is in the alley two blocks down.
أجل، أعتقد أني متأكد من أن شقتها تقع في بناية في ذلك الزقاق
Yeah, she's such a nice girl.
يا لها من فتاة لطيفة
So polite, she never fails to greet me.
إنها مهذبة جدًا وتلقي علي التحية دائمًا
Anna?
آنا)؟)
Yeah, she's such a good girl.
أجل، إنها فتاة جيدة
Always has a smile when she speaks.
دائمًا تبتسم حين تتكلم
Do you know what floor and room she lives in?
أتعرفين في أي طابق وغرفة تقيم؟
Yeah, up there.
أجل، هناك
Third floor, that window.
تلك النافذة في الطابق الثالث
If what the kids say is true...
إن كان ما قاله الأطفال حقًا
and if Milos was really kidnapped by that woman...
وإن كان (ميلوش) اختُطف حقًا من طرف تلك الفتاة
and that Anna girl is really her, then...
وكانت تلك الفتاة هي نفسها (آنا)
Then if that person is who I think he is...
وأيضًا، إن كانت هي نفسها الشخص الذي أظن
Everything will end here and now!
!فإن كل شيء سينتهي هنا والآن
They got away already?
هل غادرا من هنا؟
Where did Milos go?
أين ذهب (ميلوش)؟
Or was he kidnapped?
لا، بل أين اختُطف؟
He was following the blonde girl in order to prove my innocence.
لقد كان يتبع الفتاة الشقراء لغرض إثبات براءتي
What should we do now, Dr. Tenma?
ما العمل الآن، طبيب (تينما)؟
What expression should I make in this situation?
أي تعبير يجب أن أظهره في هذه الحالة؟
The kids got dragged into this case because they wanted to prove my innocence.
الأطفال ورَّطوا أنفسهم في هذه القضية من أجل إثبات براءتي
The kids told us, right?
لقد قال الأطفال ذلك صحيح؟
That Milos usually wanders the streets of Prague...
بأن (ميلوش) معتاد على التسكع في شوارع (براغ)
looking for his mother.
بحثًا عن أمه
He wanted... to meet his mother.
كان يريد... لقاء أمه
I... felt nothing, even when my own child died.
أنا... لم أشعر بشيء، حتى عندما مات ولدي
One day, back when I was still working for the newspapers...
يومًا ما، حين كنتُ لا أزال أعمل في الصحيفة
a female colleague told me...
قالت لي إحدى زميلاتي
that she liked me.
بأنها تحبني
So I married her...
فتزوجتُها
because I was taught that you're less likely to be suspected as a spy...
لأنه قيل لي بأنه سيكون أبعد للشك بأني جاسوس لو تزوجتُ
She got pregnant...
حملت زوجتي، وأنجبت طفلًا
Then one day, my wife was out shopping nearby.
ويومًا ما، خرجت زوجتي لغرض التسوق
When I entered my son's room...
وحين دخلتُ لغرفة ولدي
he was lying face down and had stopped breathing.
وجدتُه مستلقيًا وقد توقف عن التنفس
I gave him CPR...
قمتُ بالإنعاش القلبي الرئوي، واستدعيتُ الطبيب
I did everything I knew I should do, without hesitation.
فعلتُ كل ما يجب علي فعله، دون تردد
But he still died.
لكن الموت لم يمهله
At the funeral, my wife broke down...
وفي جنازته، صرخت زوجتي في وجهي
"How can you remain so calm?"
"كيف تظل هادئًا هكذا؟"
"Why can't you cry?"
"لماذا لا تستطيع البكاء؟"
"You're always like this."
"أنت دائمًا هكذا"
"That's how you treat me, too."
"وهكذا تعاملني أيضًا "
"You're unable to love another person."
"أنت عاجز عن حب أي إنسان"
"There's nothing in your heart."
"لا يوجد شيء في قلبك"
And then my wife left me.
وهكذا، تركتني زوجتي
We have to find Milos!
يجب أن نجد (ميلوش)
You said Milos was the child of a prostitute in the red-light district...
قلتَ بأن (مليوش) هو ابن إحدى عاهرات شارع الدعارة قرب حدود التشيك؟
Yeah...
أجل
If the person who was living here is who I think he is...
إن كان الشخص الذي يقيم هنا هو من أظن
I don't think he'll let the boy live.
فلا أظن أنه سيبقي على حياة الطفل
But he won't simply kill the boy either.
لكن، لن يكتفي بقتل الطفل ببساطة
If that person is who I think he is...
إن كان هو الشخص الذي أظن
he'll put the boy through the cruelest thing...
فإنه سيجعل الطفل يفكر في أكثر الأشياء قسوة، قبل قتله
If you keep going down this road, you'll be in Germany.
هذا الطريق سيقودك إلى ألمانيا
And my mom is somewhere down this road?
وأمي في مكان ما من هذا الطريق؟
There's a very lively place up ahead.
ثمة مكان حاشد هناك
I'll be able to see my mom, right?
وسألتقي أمي هناك؟
I'll wait for you here.
سأنتظرك هنا
Go on ahead by yourself.
اذهب بنفسك
You'll be able to recognize your mother when you see her.
ستتعرف على أمك حالما تراها
And your mom will recognize you when she sees you.
وستتعرف أمك عليك حالما تراك
But if no one calls out to you...
لكن، إن لم ينادِ عليك أحد
that means nobody wanted you.
فمعنى ذلك أنه لا أحد يريدك
What will you do then?
ماذا ستفعل حينها؟
What will you do?
ماذا ستفعل؟
Go on now.
اذهب
Mom.
أمي
Cruel, huh...
...القسوة
Thank you, thank you!
!شكرًا، شكرًا
What is it boy?
ماذا تريد يا صغير؟
I'm looking for someone.
أنا أبحث عن شخص
Looking for who?
شخص؟ من هو؟
My mom.
أمي
Your mom?!
أمك؟
That's a good one!
!طريفة
What's so funny?
ما المضحك؟
Yeah, I know your mother...
لا شيء، أنا أعرف أمك
Where...
...أين
Where is she?
أين هي؟
Well, you see...
...حسنًا
Technically, I know like...
...أعتقد أني أعرف
fifty of them here!
!خمسة منهن هنا
Why were you abandoned?
لماذا تركتك؟
Ah, my boy!
!طفلي
Who are you, lady?
من أنت يا عمة؟
It's okay.
لا بأس لا بأس
Umm, I'm looking for my mother...
لكن، أنا أبحث عن أمي
Never mind that, just let me hold you.
لا بأس، فقط دعني أحضنك
What's with the kid?
ما مشكلة هذا الطفل؟
Don't tell me that's your son.
لا تقولي لي أنه ابنك
No way!
!مستحيل
I wouldn't screw up like that.
!لستُ بهذا الغباء
Even though you're infected...
أنتِ فقط تلتقطين الأمراض
Shut up!
!اخرسي
You wanna fight?
تريدين الشجار؟
What's your problem?
ما مشكلتك؟
Let go of me!
!ابتعدي عني
Wait, not here!
!انتظر، ليس هنا
I already paid you.
لقد دفعتُ لك
I'm a customer.
أنا زبون
Do what your customer tells you to do.
افعلي ما يأمرك به زبونك
But wait...
لكن انتظر
A kid's watching!
!هناك طفل ينظر
Wait.
انتظر
keep watching.
استمر في المشاهدة
Don't leave.
لا تذهب
I'm a teacher in Germany.
أنا أستاذ في ألمانيا
At my school, I have a good reputation with the parents.
في مدرستي، أملك سمعة جيدة مع الآباء
I'm an honorable man, and a wonderful teacher.
أنا رجل شريف، وأستاذ رائع
A wonderful teacher!
!أستاذ رائع
Please take that.
خذ هذه
Who wanted you?
من أرادك؟
Hey, boy...
...يا صغير
Money...
...المال
Are you sick, lady?
هل أنت مريضة يا عمتي؟
Soon...
...قريبًا
I'm gonna die soon.
سأموت قريبًا
Why are you here?
لماذا أنتِ هنا؟
I just told you, because I'm gonna die soon.
لأني سأموت قريبًا
Money, please.
المال، أرجوك
I only have this much.
هذا كل ما أملك
Almost everything in this world is meant to die.
كل شيء في هذا العالم مصيره الموت
Who wanted you?
من أرادك؟
What is your reason for living?
ما هو هدف حياتك؟
I see...
فهمت
That's how it is.
هكذا إذًا
The red-light district ends around here.
شارع الدعارة ينتهي هنا
Lots of people saw Milos in the district.
كثيرون رأوا (ميلوش) في الشارع
Should we turn back?
هل يجب أن نعود؟
He may still be in there somewhere...
لا بد أنه في مكان ما هنا
Milos!
!(ميلوش)
Milos...
(ميلوش)
It's all right...
لا تقلق
Okay...
حسنًا
Come to me.
تعال إلي
In order to...
...من أجلي
In order to prove my innocence...
من أجل إثبات براءتي
You tried your best, right?
ألم تبذل أفضل ما لديك؟
It's all right now.
لا بأس الآن
Come here.
تعال إلي
It's all right...
لا بأس
It's all right now.
لا بأس عليك
Is this how I'm supposed to feel, Dr. Tenma?
هل هذا ما يجب أن أشعر به، طبيب (تينما)؟
Would it be better if I cried?
هل سيكون أفضل لو بكيتُ؟
I was never taught...
...لم أتعلم قط
such complicated feelings.
هذه المشاعر المعقدة
What's wrong, Milos?
ما الأمر، (ميلوش)؟
What did you see...
ما الذي رأيته؟
What did you see back there?
ما الذي رأيته هناك؟
What have you experienced?
ما الذي جربتَه؟
Milos, listen to me.
ميلوش)، أصغ إلي)
You don't have a mother.
أنت لا تملك أمًا
But...
...لكن
There is a reason why you were born!
!هناك سبب وُلدتَ لأجله
You were born because someone wanted you!
!لقد وُلدتَ لأن شخصًا ما أرادك
You were definitely...
...حتمًا
You were definitely wanted by someone!
حتمًا، أرادك شخص ما
Hey, Dr. Tenma...
أخبرني، طبيب (تينما)
What I just said isn't wrong, is it?
ما قلتُه ليس خاطئًا، صحيح؟
No.
نعم
Right now...
...الآن
What kind...
...أي تعبير
What kind of expression do I have?
أي تعبير يبدو علي؟
You're crying.
أنت تبكي